Guide to the Michael La Vean French documents collection, 1751-1851
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Michael La Vean French documents collection
1751-1851
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Michael La Vean
C0078
3 linear feet (8 boxes)
The La Vean collection contains 268 documents and books from the period between 1751 and 1851. The majority of the documents come from the years between the creation of the French National Assembly in 1789 and the beginning of the Empire in 1805.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Michael La Vean in 2004.
Biographical Information
Michael La Vean is an entrepreneur and medical device patent holder who studied Business Administration at George Mason University. He spent seven years in Rennes, France, and collects books and documents, especially those relevant to politics and the history of women in eighteenth and nineteenth century France.
Scope and Content
The La Vean collection contains 268 documents and books from the period between 1751 and 1851. It includes copies of legislation by the French constitutional monarchy and the evolving Republic; administrative correspondence and official records from Morbihan; a few London newspapers mentioning France; ten books, notably a 1797 edition of Three Memorials on French Affairs by Sir Edmund Burke; and other materials. The majority of the documents come from the years between the creation of the French National Assembly in 1789 and the beginning of the Empire in 1805.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the La Vean Collection that consists of multiple volumes on the French Revolution donated by Michael La Vean. The books can be found by searching for "La Vean Collection" in the GMU Libraries catalog.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
France--History--First Republic, 1792-1804.; France--History--Revolution, 1789-1799.
Contents List
- Michael La Vean French documents collection
  - Observations on the response made to his discourse, Pamphlet by J.J. Rousseau 1751 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Pamphlet ;12.5cm by 20cm
  - Response to M. Gautier's Refutation of his Discourse, Copy of Pamphlet "letter" from J.J. Rousseau of Geneva Nov. 1st, 1751 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Receipt stating that Gouroussau repaid the sum of 3 thousand livres; Signed: Rousmade 23rd April 1770 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Receipt ;23.5cm by 11cm
  - A New Geographical Grammar; History of Geography with maps and explanation in the form of a dialogue between a master and his scholar. By Charles Vyse; Second Edition 1779 (Box 7)
    Book; 10 x 17.5 x 4.5 cm; 479 pages
  - Etrennes Bretonnes, Géographiques, Historiques, Ecclésiastiques, Civiles; Summary of the State of the Region of Brittany for the year of 1785 1785 (Box 7)
    Book ;6 x 11.5 x 1 cm.
    Almanac from 1785
  - Printed first-hand account of the fall of the Bastille from Cousin Jacques editor of "Courier des Planètes" read to the Marquis de la Salle and the members of his committee. 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    lettter ;13.5cm by 21.5cm
  - Pamphlet "letter" to LeCompte de Mirabeau, Representative of the National Assembly from a French officer on The Natural Character of French and Foreign Soldiers and Officers. June 25, 1789 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Pamphlet "letter" ;13.5cm by 21cm
  - Newspaper: "Journal de Paris", No. 236 August 24, 1789 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Newspaper; 16cm by 22cm
    The National Assembly, the Academy of Architecture; Theater reviews, etc.
  - Newspaper: "Journal de Paris" No. 323 Thursday Nov. 19, 1789 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Newspaper ;16cm by 22cm
    Proceedings of the Assemblée Nationale; Administration, Theater Review.
  - Receipt: Debt paid by Louault; Signed: Foussé February 9, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Receipt ;17cm by 21cm
  - Discours Prononcés in September 1790 à la Tribune de l' assemblée constituante; Written by Mirabeau La Gallissonnière, Beaumetz, du Pont de Nemours, l'Abbé Maury, Montesquieu, l'éveque d'Autun, Talleyrand. September 1790 (Box 7)
    Booklet; 16.5 x 25 cm; published 1926
  - Copy of Law No. 564 by the National Assembly; signers:: LOUIS and M.L.F. Duport; Re: Estate taxes. February 18, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    law copy ;22cm by 27cm
  - Copy of Law No. 1254; From the National Assembly; No signatures. Re: New stewards of the record to take over their functions in 15 days. September 12, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    law copy; 21cm by 29cm
  - Copy of law from the National Assembly Re: Military court policy in case of request for clemency by a jury; Signed for the king by M. L. F. Dufort September 12 1791 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Copy of law ;20cm by 27cm
  - Copy of the King's letter to the National Assembly expressing eagerness to accept the new constitution and continue to reform the French state. September 13 1791 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Letter copy ;15.5cm by 19cm
  - Real estate income from the District of War Nov. 22 1791 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    statement ;24.5cm by 38.5cm
    Signed: The Adminstrators of St. Maximin; Re: Date and Amount of payments. Wax seal.
  - Outline "Sketch" of the new constitution of France (in English) by Thomas Christie, dedicated to M. de la Rochefoucalud. 1791 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Proclamation ;39cm by 55.5cm
  - Notice to the citizens of Avignon Re: Elections for departmental commissioners April 14th 1792 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Notice ;36cm by 46.5cm
    (oversized)
  - Newspaper "Journal de Paris" No. 3 April 20th 1792 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Newspaper ;17cm by 22cm
    Re: News of the National Assembly
  - Copy of the law by the National Assembly 22 April, 1792 l'an 4 de la liberté stating that all old regime flags and symbols must be replaced and burned. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    legislation ;29 x 39.5 cm
    signers:: LOUIS and Duranthan; printed by Descéne in Aix
  - Copy of a law No. 1695 from the National Assembly Re: Additional financing for the navy. May 4, 1792 (year 4) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    law copy ;21cm by 25.5cm
    Signed: Louis, Duranthon
  - Copy of a law No. 1839; From the National Assembly Re: Abolition of feudal laws. July 6 1792; year 4 (sic) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    law copy ;21cm by 28cm
    Signed: LOUIS, Dejoly
  - Copy of a law No. [ ] Re: the wealth held by the clergy. August 17th, 1792; year 4 [sic] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    law copy ;21cm by 26cm
    Printed signature: Rolland, Countersigned- Danton, Descene. Letterhead has been cut out. Large stains. Missing text.
  - Copy of law No. 2237; From the National Assembly Re: Restrictions on the awarding of passports for the members of the legislative corps. August 27 1792; year 4 [sic] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Law copy ;21cm by 26cm
    Signed: Servan, countersigned Danton
  - Proclamation by the Provisional Executive Council Re: Economic problems with circulation and distribution; defense of free market. October 31, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Proclamation ;21cm by 26.5cm
    Signed: Roland, Monge, Pache, Garat, Claviere and Le Brum
  - Proclamation by the Provisional Executive Council Re: removal of the exemption from housing troops from the Order of Malthe After 30 September 1792 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Proclamation ;21 x 26.5 cm
  - Decree No. 113 from the National Convention Re: Right of electors passes to those present in cases of incomplete number of electors. November 1st 1792 (year 1) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Decree ;21cm by 26.5cm
    Signed Garat, President of Provisional Executive Council
  - 10 volume list of 2,742 people listed condemned to guillotine with their professions and the charges against them 1793 (Box 1, Folder (258))
    Pamphlet ;14 x 22 cm
    chez Channaud and Berthé
  - The Gentleman's Magazine May 1793 (Box 1, Folder (259))
    Magazine ;13 x 20.5 x 1 cm
    Publ. Fleet Street; Sylvanus Urban, Ed.
  - Décret; Copy No. 115 Re: Compensation for manual laborers on the "camp sous Paris" November 2 1792, year 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Decree ;19.5cm by 25cm
    Signed: (Peint) Garat, and Dinome
  - Proclamation by the Three Administrative Corps and the Commissioners of the Departments in Marseille Re: 24 hour deadline to report any émigrés or be denounced as a traitor. November 11 1792 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Signed: Villiard, Granet, Mourraille, Descene
  - Decree No. 328 Re: Motion to try those accused in August and September rebellion 20 January 1793 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Proclamation ;20.5 x 26.5cm
    signers:: Garat; Descene
  - Proclamation by the Commissioners of the National Convention in the Meridional Maritime Departments Re: Call to courage and union after the fall of the monarchy. 8 February 1793 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Proclamation ;21cm by 27cm
    Signed: Rouyer, Le Tourneur, Brunel.
  - Newspaper: "The Star" (London) May 27, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Newspaper ;33 cm by 49cm
    Re: National and International news and feature articles. (Battle at Famars; release of officers held prisoner) (folded)
  - Abstract of law November 26th, 1792 and May, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    legal document ;not found
    Schedule of charges to be paid by the state to families of active duty soldiers; torn
  - Decree from the National Convention Re: actions taken in response to rebellion against the republic. 24th day, of June 1793, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Decree ;20cm by 23cm
    Signed: by le Vasseur, R. Lindet, Billaud-Varenne, Secretaries S. E. Monneand, Rovère Poultier.
  - Decree No. 1501 Re: Organization and compensation for the corps of volunteers 7 September, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Decree ;20.5 x 27 cm
  - Decree No.1749 From the National Convention, the Minister of the Navy, stating that naval officers in training will remain in school and will not be faced with conscription. 18th September 1793, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Decree ;20.5cm by 26cm
    Signed: Desforgues, Countersigned: Gottier.
  - Table of types of counterfeit bills in circulation up until September 21, year 2 September 21, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Table ;22cm by 27cm
  - Decree No. 1652 Re: military justice is equivalent to civilian court under the appellation "criminal court" 3 October, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Decree ;20.5 x 26.5 cm
    torn
  - Decree No. 1745 From the National Convention, Paris Re: The administrative corps is to decide on cases of certificates of residence. 17th day, month 1, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Decree ;20.5 by 25cm
    Original approved: Bouillerot, Duplicate signed: Deforgues, Countersigned: Gohier.
  - Decree No. 1747 from the National Convention Re: Beneficiaries among the navy of the law of September 12, 1791. 17th day of the first month, year 2. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Decree ;20.5cm by 26.5cm
    Signed: A. Forestz
  - Decree No. 1748 Re: Competition to determine who may study to become or obtain a post as a naval sculptor 17th day, first month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Decree ;20cm by 25.5cm
    Signed: Defargues, Countersigned; Gohien
  - Copy of Decree No. 1720 Re: Equivalent pay for inspectors, verifiers, and guards. 18th day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Decree copy ;20.5cm by 26.5cm
    Signed: (printed) S.E. Monnel, Deforgues, Gohier, Cottier-Julian
  - Copy of Decree No. 1721 Re: Military equipment and supplies to be handled by each departmental and district administration. 18th day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Decree copy ;21cm by 27cm
    Signed: (printed) S.E. Monnel, Defourgues, Monnel, Cottier-Julian
  - Copy of Decree No. 1722 Re: Financing tax to be abolished. 22nd day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Decree copy ;22cm by 26.5cm
    Signed: (in print) S.E. Monnel
  - Decree of the National Convention No. 1734 Re: The collection of rental payments on properties in Paris with pay-by dates and penalties, and with model (title certificate). 24th day of the first month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Public decree from the national convention No. 1736 Re: Bedding found in émigré housing would be given to the citizens barracks of the first requisition. 25th day of the first month of the 2nd year of the French Republic (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Decree ;21cm by 24cm
    signers:: Couttier, Julien, Sesgreff, S.E. Monnel, L. J. Charlier, President P.F. Piorry, Louis de Bas-rhin [ secretaries]; Deforgues, Gohier; handwritten signature: A. Forestz. Water stains.
  - Decree of the National Convention No. 1744 Re: letter concerning overseeing of military transport. 25th day of the first month of the 2nd year of the French Republic (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Decree ;20cm by 26cm
    Signed: Cottier-Julian, the secretary general, and by [Tiolvst], [Sergrey]. Printed.
  - Copy of Decree No. 1733 Re: The announcement of a marriage will proceed the celebration by 3 days. 25th day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Decree copy; 20cm by 26cm
    Signed: (print signature) Monnel, copy signers: -Charlier, Ramel, Piorry.
  - Copy of decree No. 1732 Re: the number of horses to be kept by the military and the customs authority. 26th day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Signed: S.E. Monnel, copy with printing-Charlier, Piorry, Ramel; Conservation needed - stains and small holes.
  - Copy of Decree No. 1727 nullifying the decree that all cash must be turned over to heads of each district in exchange for promissory notes. 26th day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Decree copy ;20.5cm by 27cm
    Signed: (printed) S.E. Monnel, Copy signed Charlier, Piorry, and Ramel. (manuscript additions).
  - Decree No. 1737 from the National Convention Re: Declaration that the surveillance committees must give an official statement and reasons for any arrests. 27th day of the first month of the 2nd year (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Signers: Bouillerot, inspector and Cottier-Julian, Secretary-General. Printed.
  - Decree No.. 1770 Re: Taxing and regulation of commercial boats. 27th day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Decree ;21.5 cm by 27cm
    Signed: S.E. Monnel; Duplicates signed: Charlier, Ramel and Pons
  - Decree No.. 1774; From the National Convention Re: Restrictions on payment of indemnities for losses by fire or accident. 1st day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Decree ;none
    Signed: Bouillerot, Duplicates signed: Bazle, Foncroy, Duval, and Louis du Bas Rhin. small tear at fold.
  - Decree No.. 1762 Re: Mandatory destruction of cities which surrender without defending themselves. first day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Signed: Bouillerot; Duplicates - Boyle, Fourcroy, Louis, Ch. Duval
  - Decree No.. 1767 Re: Reforms to the appeals system. 1st day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Decree ;21cm by 26cm
    Signed: Bouillerot, Duplicates signed - Bazle, Fourcrono, Lonis du Bas-Rhin, et ch. Duvall; [Damaged edges]
  - Decree no. 1768 Re: Reform of laws for tenant farmers' protection. 1st day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Decree ;22cm by 26.5cm
    Signed: Bouillerot, Duplicates signed: Bayle, Fourcroy, Louis de Bas Rhin and Ch. Duval. [needs conservation around the edges]
  - Decree no. 1769 that the price of cattle be capped by mutual agreement 2nd day, 2nd month, 2nd year (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Decree ;21.5cm by 26.5cm
    Signed: Bouillerot, Duplicates signed: Bayle, Fourcroy, Ch. Duval, C. Bazyre.
  - Decree no. 1773 from the National Convention Re: standard weights and measures to be made in platinum. 2nd day, 1st month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Signed: S.E. Monnel, Duplicates signed: Bayle, Fourcroy, Charles Duval, Louis du Bas-Rhin.
  - Decree no. 1784 from Paris Re: Necessity of an official accusation before allowing a case to be judged as in the case of Gen. Houchard. 3rd day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Decree ;22cm by 26cm
    Original signed: Monnel and also by Charlier, Fouray, and Basire. Torn corner.
  - Decree No. 1797 from the National Convention Re: Authorizing direct acquisition of fabrics (serge et cadis) for troops. 6th day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Signed: Bouillerot, Duplicates signed Bazle, Fourcroy, Ch. Dural.
  - Decree no. 1798 From the National Convention stating that citizens who obtained their papers from the school of engineering and artillery are subject to requisitioning by the war ministry, not the localities. 6th day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Signed: Bouillerot, Duplicates: Boyle, Fourcroy, Duval.
  - Decree no. 1796 From the National Convention in Paris Re: shortening the length of time by bringing case to a vote after 3 days with juror consent. 8th day, 2nd month, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Decree ;21.5cm by 25.5cm
    Signed: S.E. Monnel; Dups. Boyle, Fourcroy, Piorry. Torn corner.
  - Last will and Testament of Louis XVI 1793 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Will ;13cm by 22cm
    in French and Dutch
  - Decree no. 2000; From the National Convention Re: Duffan's Condemnation: Address to the army of the Eastern Pyrénées. 8 Nivôse year 2 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Decree ;21.5cm by 28.5cm
    Signer of original: Auger, others signers: Couthon, Thibeaudeau, Pellisner, and Perrin.
  - Minutes from Municipalities of Artigues Re: Account of taxes collected on real estate. 11 Nivôse year 2 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Minutes ;22.5cm by 30.5cm
    11 pages (including front and back). Signed: T. Queird, Joseph Leth.
  - Decree no. 2055; From the National Convention Re: Establishment of moving guards, and military outposts on continental and water boundaries. 15th Nivôse, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    Decree ;20.5cm by 27cm
    Signed: S.E. Monnel.
  - Decree no. 2183 stating that appointees for marches will serve until Spring. 30 Pluviôse, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Original signed: S.E. Monnel; Duplicates signed: Dubairran, Mathieu, Berhier. Torn.
  - Decree no. 2246 From the National Convention Re: Regulation and restriction of makers of money. 62nd day, Pluviôse, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Signed Auger; Duplicate signed; Rhul, Tallien, S.E. Monnel. [torn] [Needs cleaning]
  - Decree no. 2214 from the National Convention Re: establishment of policy for pearls and precious stones; only silver and gold pieces above a certain value will not be melted down. 11th Ventôse, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Decree ;22cm by 27cm
  - Proclamation by the National Convention Re: Conspiracy plot 2 Germinal, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Signed: Talien, president of the convention; Leyris, Peyssard, Pothier, Bezard, Monnel. Needs conservation
  - Copy of Decree No. 2285 Re: False Testimony before a military tribunal 14th Germinal year 2 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    Decree ;21.5cm by 27cm
    Print signatuRe: Cordier, Copy print signature - Voullard, Pottier, Monnot, Ruelle; needs cleaning
  - Copy of Decree No. 2269 from the National Convention Re: Conspiracy plot of Lacroix, Danton, Chabot and others. 15th Germinal, year 2 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Signer of original: Auges, signers of copy: Tallieh, Bezard, Mounel. Some stains; needs cleaning.
  - Copy of Decree no. 2296 Re: Regulating the price of stage coaches in Haute Seine, Saone and Rhone. 17th Germinal, year 2 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    Decree ;21cm by 27.5cm
    Print SignatuRe: Cordier; Copy: Voullard, Pottier, Leyris.
  - Abstract of a law by the National Convention at the behest of the committee for public safety Re: ways to increase manufacture of potash. 29th Germinal; year 2 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    Abstract of law; 21cm by 27cm
    Signed: Billaud-Varenne, Couthon, Robespierre, Carnot, Lindet, Collot d'Herbois, Prieur.
  - Report on public safety given at the National Convention Re: Political opposition to the chouans. 1st Floréal year 2 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    Report ;21cm by 27cm
    Printed signature: Amar, Pottier, Ruelle, Monnot, Peyssara, Leyris, and Baudot.
  - Extract from the register of decisions by the committee of public safety Re: Production of nitric and sulfuric acid. 23rd Floréal year 2 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    Extract ;21cm by 26cm
    Signed: Robespierre, Barere, Carnot, Prieur, Lindet, Billaud-Varenne, Conthan, Collot d'Herbois. Stained.
  - Copy of Decree No. 2379 from the National Convention Re: Handling of life insurance. 9th Prairial, year 2 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    Decree copy ;9th Prairial, year 2
    Signed: (print) Cordier; Alias - Voullard, Carrier, Francastel.
  - List No. 30: account of losses at the house of citizen Lorau, aubergiste, during the counter-revolutionary war. Vendémiaire, year 3 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    List ;11cm by 18cm
  - Receipt Re: 300 livres owned by Louaul[s] to citizen Bance, notary. 20th Brumaire, year 3 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    Receipt ;21cm by 13cm
    No signatures.
  - Letter no. 33 From Yves le Roi to the National Convention Re: Destruction to property and threats made by brigands against le Roi and family. 3rd Frimaire, year 3 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    Letter ;22cm by 34.5cm
    No signatures. Damaged upper right corner.
  - Affidavit/signed official statement from Pontivy Re: Farm in Josselin belonging to Cosmé Briens, First Municipal Officer of Naizin. 25th Nivôse year 3 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    Affidavit ;21.5cm by 18cm
    Signed: Guepin, Ledbare, D[unay]
  - Copy of Law No. 129 made in Loir et Cher Re: Monetary reforms; organization of the military; outstanding debts; payments of engineers; regional representatives; soldiers' families, organization of new government. 14th Ventôse year 3 (Folder 79, Box 3)
    Law copy ;14cm by 22cm
    signers:: Monnel and Viquy
  - List no. 12; From Jacques Eonet de Naizin to the committee on war damages Re: Stolen household goods; list with total price. 24th Prairial, year 3 (Folder 80, Box 3)
    List ;19.5cm by 24.5cm
    Signed: J. Eonet
  - Letter no. 7 From Anne le Brucher in Naizin to the committee in charge of reparations Re: Total losses in Francs with list of each offense. year 3 or 4 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    Letter ;19.5cm by 23.5cm
    Part of bottom page damaged.
  - Letter no. 33 From the Minister of the Interior in Paris to the Department of Morbihan Re: claims of Cosmé Briens and Leroy for reparations on property damaged in the war. 9 Frimaire, year 4 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    Letter ;18.5cm by 24cm
    Signed: [Derniau]
  - Promissory note [Promesse de mandat territorial bon pour 25 francs] 28 ventôse, year 4 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    mandat ;23 x 10 cm
  - Circular From Vannes to Lominé Re: arrest of a wigmaker in Lominé 30 nivôse, year 4 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    circular ;none
  - Circular; From the acting commissioner of the executive director of the central administration of the Department of Morbihan in Vannes to the municipal commissioner of Locminé Re: careful surveillance of passports of people coming from Bremen. 5th Prairial year 4 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    Circular ;17cm by 21cm
    Signed: [faveroz].
  - Letter from the provisional commissioner of the executive director of Morbihan to the municipal commissioners of Lominé Re: Recommendation of arrest of Chevaller Dormenan, émigré returned to France. 15 messidor, year 4 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    Letter ;18cm by 22cm
    Signed: Faveroz.
  - Letter. From the Commissioner of the Executive Directory of Morbihan to the Commissioners of Loeminé Re: Forwarding a letter from the Minister of the Police advocating surveillance of party leaders. 4th Thermidor, year 4 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    Letter ;20cm by 30.5cm
  - Abstract of the registry of deliberations. From the central administration of Morbihan. Re: Repentant chouans. 24 Thermidor year 4 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    Abstract ;20cm by 31cm
    Needs conservation. Water stains on back.
  - Public Safety Circular from Vannes Commissary to the administration of Lominé to prevent people from making their new homes in the woods to prevent danger of fire. 24th of Thermidor, year 4 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    Public Safety Circular ;12.5cm by 19.5cm
    Signed by Lauzen, Faveroz, [Leunnefrine] [Le Mouraift].